Marcelo Palacio

Senior Web Developer

https://marcelo-palacio.netlify.app/

San Luis 1170 Corrientes, W 3400 Argentina

SUMMARY

I started my career as a software developer and quickly discovered that my true passion centered around web, blockchain development.

As getting a bachelor's at Universidad CAECE, I have got 6+ years of experience in computer networks architecture and software design patterns, as well as practicing many web frameworks in real-world projects.

My major skills in web development are JavaScript frameworks such as React/Vue.js for the frontend and Node.js/Express for the backend.

While using these JavaScript frameworks, I got the ropes of Redux pattern, React Hooks, etc. What makes me proud of myself is my career in developing many real-world projects. Through those opportunities, I have been familiar with CI/CD pipelines and QA automation using Jest, Docker, etc.

I am also familiar with PHP frameworks such as Laravel and this is the first framework that I am fascinated with when starting my career as a web developer.

In addition, I have experience in building smart contracts with Solidity, creating cryptocurrencies on Ethereum and BSC. I have also built NFT marketplace on Ethereum network.

My passion for these areas drives me to constantly learning and improving, boosting my skills. I have my heart set on being one of the top developers in this area.

SKILLS

Frontend Development

React/Redux/Next.js Vue.js/Nuxt.js Node.js Material UI/Tailwind CSS/BootStrap Web3.js

Backend Development

Node.js ExpressJS NestJS Laravel Django MySQL MongoDB PostgreSQL

Programming Language

JavaScript PHP Python TypeScript GraphQL Solidity

EDUCATION

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Universidad CAECE

@2010 - 2015

GPA

- · I majored computer science and got a bachelor's degree
- · I published highly assessed thesis during the academic period
- I took part in many real-world projects

3.7 / 4.0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Developer

Gonni

@ 04/2015-5/2017 Buenos Aires

IT/Network Company

- · Gained experience in Front-end Developing experience
- · I mostly worked on the project with React, Vue, and Node.js
- · Pixel perfect following design

Senior Developer

Rootstrap

@ 06/2017- 07/2020 Buenos Aires

- · I worked as Full Stack Developer.
- Used React/Next.js, Vue.js/Nuxt.js, Laravel, NodeJS Framework and web3.js, ether.js for getting info about the providers

Web/Blockchain development

@ 2020 - 2022

- Mainly work as a lead/senior full -stack developer with React, Vue.js, Node.js
- Familiar with CI / CD pipelines, Get Version Control, Docker, AWS web hosting
- · Smart contract, Dapp development
- Experience in building NFT marketplace, token creation(ERC20, BEP20)

LANGUAGES

Spanish

English fluent

Native